[Music]
the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet resume of
holography
hello everyone this is Frankie Freitas
it's 11 o'clock on Thursday night and
we're live on the world wide web hello
everyone how are you uh we're going to
be showing the Kennedy assassination
test bullets tonight this is a project
that I'm working on doing holograms for
Jerry Robinson who has put out a work
called denial the truth behind these
fascination of President John F Kennedy
and we're going to see live in just a
few minutes what these bullets look like
one of the first team bullet looks like
it has never been fired from a rifle and
it is very similar to The Once
International archives that supposedly
did all the damage to Kennedy and
Governor John Connolly
and the other bullet is a bullet that
was taken and fired into the cadaver's
wrist
show what type of damage would happen
just from going through a wrist because
the other bullet the pristine bullet
actually went through Kennedy's neck
exited his neck
until you go on the limousine
Governor Conley in the back puncturing
his lung exiting the front of his chest
hitting him in the wrist shattering all
the bones and the rest of them passing
through the wrist and embedding itself
into his thigh and after all that damage
the pristine bullet supposedly was found
on Governor Connolly's stretcher it
worked its way out of his spy and yet we
see this other bullet
where the only thing he did was fired
into a cadaver's wrist and you should
see the damage of that and we're just
going to see in a few seconds
here on the show 11 10 and 11 20.
excuse me I'm going to put these images
up next week we've got something
interesting if you've ever wanted to
know what a hologram is exactly
tune into the live webcam next Thursday
night the 28th at 11 PM and I'm going to
take several Holograms and put them
under a high-powered microscope and
broadcast those live images on the world
wide web for you to see exactly on a
microscopic level what makes up a
holographic image because as you know if
you pick up a hologram and hold it in
the light
see a three-dimensional image but if you
take that hologram and just look through
it if it's not in a frame or anything
it's just like a clear piece of glass so
just like the glass that's in your
window of your home that you can see
right through only when the light hits
that hologram at a certain angle
holographic image appear and they're
actually
fringes interference patterns that make
up this holographic image on a
microscopic scale so we're going to take
the webcam attach it to the microscope
and during the show we're going to put
several Holograms under the microscope
and you'll be able to see what makes up
a holographic image on the microscopic
scale I've taken a look at it already
it's fairly interesting it's something
you may want to tune in to see our
special guest this week is Dr John Perry
whole graphics North in Burlington
Vermont and if you've ever wondered what
it would be like to create large
Holograms and large by large I mean
three and a half by six feet in size and
working on a table that's 12 feet wide
by 22 feet long in fact this table is so
big
they walk around on the table to set up
the Optics they just get right on the
table and walk around on it so uh he's
going to fill us in on what it's like to
work
at that end of holography when the large
format the Holograms and he's coming up
in just a moment
I've got another guest in the studio
with me right now
special guest as well it's my daughter
safe Faith how are you tonight I'm okay
how are you doing okay we just got faith
back from college our first year
and faith is majoring in physics with a
minor in
mathematics how did the first year go
it was a lot of fun
are you telling the truth yes I am it
was fun it was difficult but very
rewarding
now what do you hope to do
with the major in physics
well after I finished undergraduate
school I'd like to go to graduate school
to get my PhD
hopefully in astrophysics and someday
work for NASA
you know John Perry's an astrophysicist
at the University of Vermont
now what did you cover this year did you
have any Optics
towards the end of the semester we had a
little bit but we didn't go into detail
Optics is pretty tough I guess right
figuring out the path of light and
things yeah the mathematics behind it
yeah it's harder than regular physical
well the rest of it
and we'll probably pick that up next
year right next spring they're offering
you know six of course
and lasers and Holograms this year not
this year I'm surprised that they don't
uh you know I I run laser and holography
classes for students
down as far as third grade believe it or
not I'm surprised that they wouldn't
bring bleachers and Holograms into a
first-year physical asset that for no
other reason than to uh
show the students what cool things can
be done using lasers and and physics
behind
holography itself I had your physics
professor in one of my classes yeah I'm
aware of that yeah my daughter's physics
Professor was a student in one of my
laser holography classes at Lehigh
University back in the 80s and she found
it very very interesting and she pursued
well her background's in crystals right
or something yeah
I also want to congratulate you
on your recent appointment
to being the president of the Society of
physics students at the
end chapter of it yeah yeah
um I started an astronomy club this year
we went up to the uh my dorm to look at
the stars and that was sort of through
the society but I did it on my own I got
the key from my professor we went up
there every Wednesday night to look at
the stars when it was clear
a lot of fun they have a nice telescope
up there yeah they have a few pretty big
telescopes oh really yeah
well
it's good to have you back home nice to
be back home
okay well I always wanted to get you on
the show thank you for being a guest on
my show thanks for inviting me
okay let's move on
well why don't we start off I'll let our
listeners know that we're speaking with
Dr John Perry who has a company is it
still in Burlington Vermont still in
Burlington still in Burlington and the
company is holographics north and I
would I'd say it's safe to assume to say
that your company's known for a large
format holography that's definitely our
specialty okay that's right
would you tell us a little bit about the
holographic services that you offer for
your clients sure we make display
Holograms up to sizes uh three and a
half by six feet which would be about
1.1
by 1.8 meters
we make quite light transmission we do
some reflection work not that big it's
mostly white light transmission work
what we call Rainbow work
a good deal of what we do these days is
stereogram holography which means we can
start with essentially movie footage so
we can we can enlarge and reduce images
we can shoot on site we can shoot in
flood lighting instead of laser lighting
we can animate the subjects uh probably
most of the listeners aren't familiar
with stereograms we can also work with
computer models and those can be
animated morphed
um we can do full color uh we don't do a
lot of it but we've done some full color
the clientele tends to be trade show
corporations doing trade show booths
museums mostly science related museums
Technology Centers that's very
International Market and artists who
have projects that are funded and they
come to us pretty much as Fabricators to
produce the work for them and often
they're in Residence here when we do
that most of us could probably not even
comprehend making a whole Grand outside
I'd say the biggest part of the audience
would work with maybe four by five inch
plates in their homes and schools I
would imagine working with film up size
is a little bit like working with
wallpaper isn't it I wish it was that
easy although wallpaper has its own
problems of course we're working on film
as you said and uh holding the film has
its own peculiar problems but probably
the worst part to the most difficult
part of large format is that
although the the difficulties in
stabilizing all the optical elements and
stabilizing the film that the difficulty
of doing that increases probably with
the area of the film I would say so
we're we're probably a hundred times uh
something like that more difficult than
an 8 by 10 inch the tolerances that were
allowed are just the same yeah we still
have to be stable to roughly a millionth
of an inch
so it is extremely difficult it's taken
many years really it took about a decade
to to really feel comfortable with the
processes that we use to be able to do
that and our location is critical uh
Burlington Vermont is not only a great
place to live but it's quiet there's no
train system coming in the airport's
over the hill from us and it's a it's a
pretty pretty low vibration area that
we're in and we're in a we're in an Old
Brick School building pretty solid one
um in a residential area of town and
we're in the basement of course with
nice 11 foot ceilings it's really great
basement and the foundation of is three
feet of solid stone with about two feet
of brick above it so it's a it's a great
location if I remember correctly from a
story I read about your company maybe in
whole sphere back in and inside which
pain you actually work on a floor
instead of a table right the floor
itself is isolated to vibration did you
pour like a large concrete floor or
something that's right we we call it a
table but we step right onto it I mean
it's that floor level uh frankly our
landlord at the time insisted on this he
wouldn't let us pour a concrete slab
three feet above the floor it's 12 by 22
feet and it's 14 inches thick that's a
lot of concrete
and one of the advantages to floor level
is of course you can just step right on
and walk around you don't have to climb
up climb down we have more Headroom over
it of course by doing that also but
another Advantage more practically is
that someday if somebody puts that room
to other uses all they have to do is
tile the tile the table basically and
it's a floor again
um the concrete has reinforcement and
it's not steel it's fiberglass
reinforcement we basically dug a utoll
in the ground and and filled it up with
snow which we have plenty of here and
then poured the concrete on top of the
snow and with a little blue board in
between to keep the heat of the curing
from from melting the snow too fast and
then by the time the snow was melting
out the concrete had set enough to to
support itself there are four legs that
that hold the whole thing up and a
fairly complicated structure actually
underneath that kind of supports all
that concrete
and that all sits on Piers that go down
through sleeves uh 15 inch diameter
sleeves they could add about 14 feet and
then they're anchored directly into the
Glacial Hill is really what it is um
deep under the building so we don't
float the table is not pneumatically
suspended but it's isolated from the
building vibrations we pick up ground
vibrations but not building vibrations
again it's a quiet neighborhood
yeah I can imagine when you have enough
distance you can spread a laser a laser
beam out
to cover that area of a plate but do you
use collimation also well yes and no our
reference beams uh on transfers and also
on shooting Masters are not collimated
uh they're spreading over lengths of 20
to 35 feet depending on just what we're
doing so it's a pretty good long throw
so that's what counts as far as how
close you are to collimation is the
distance from from the point source
basically from the spatial filter
so that's pretty good when we're
Illuminating Masters we do have a
one-dimensional column here we have a
curved mirror a strip mirror about 60
inches long and curved in that long
Dimension it's curved to about a 13 and
a half foot radius let me correct that
it's a 13 and a half foot focal length
of the curve is so we can
um when we illuminate Masters we can
produce an exact conjugate of the of the
reference Beam with which the master was
shot so we don't get any distortion
rejected image from the master and
that's really the important part uh the
reference on the transfers is not
collimated and of course the
illumination beam later is also not
collimated and cannot copy that but
but that's not as critical since the
images is image plane at that point what
are some of your latest projects that
you've worked on well we just put six
Holograms onto the Grand Princess
um if you're not familiar is the biggest
cruise ship in the world um 2.2 times
the size of the Titanic in volume
um it was being built in Northern Italy
I was over there about a month ago to
just checking the lighting specs and
those Holograms are installed the ship
sailing but not in not in commercial
service yet it'll be another couple of
weeks and I'm getting good feedback I'm
getting feedback that they are a great
attraction they're in the casino what
were the content mostly underwater
scenery uh two of them are computer
generated one was Dolphins um mama and a
baby dolphin diving down through the
water and then arcing back up again as
you walk by the Hologram and a lot of
flora and fauna and start
lots of little fish of all kinds sort of
floating around and doing a lot of
seahorses in that one little Tails
wiggling and stuff it's a great image
it's in two colors it's six feet wide
wow and about three feet three and a
half feet tall yeah it's our maximum
size three and a half by six and lots of
Animation
um which is why the lighting was a
concern to be sure we had a good long
white path uh the other big one the
other three and a half by six foot
hologram there are two of those
um
uh stingrays kind of a flock of them
should we say flying or floating or
swimming out toward you as you walk by
and then there's a lot of fan coral and
fish and fish a big
shark in the background kind of filling
up the middle of the frame so there's a
lot going on in there and the third one
was not a stereogram it's a it's a
should we say a traditional hologram of
a turtle we have a great stuffed turtle
here
Dixie Turtle about three feet long and
it's a two channel so he moves as you
walk by but in a sudden one sudden jump
and a lot of Flora and Fauna in that one
too so they're they're great they're
just wonderful images
so use that holographic table just about
the same way that someone would set
something up in the theater at that size
uh pretty much it's a lot of fun
I have to walk you know 10 or 15 feet
just to get from one side of the subject
to the other sometimes
as the active situation had an impact on
what you're doing yet well
um it's had an impact on my banker I
guess I've I've stockpiled about a
five-year supply of a large roll film
and we we have that I mean it was
delivered last fall seems to be pretty
good quality
um and I've got it pretty well uh you
know pretty well wrapped up and in a
dehumidified environment so that'll last
us hopefully until something else comes
along I think slavish uh it looks pretty
good it's slow filmed the new film made
in Lithuania appears to be a pretty good
substitute except it's going to take a
lot more energy unless they can do some
of that then what do you think like a 5
or 20 watt argon no uh this may surprise
you we use a 50 milliwatt helium neon oh
really like one of the 125s that we have
three 125. that's exactly what we have
two of them have adelons retrofitted
into them for uh increased coherence and
of course we get lots of coherence about
15 meters so we can shoot
you know we measure our path lengths but
we get them within three or four feet
and don't worry about it and
um and those uh we just we just kind of
count our photons one at a time I mean
we save them very carefully and try not
to waste light and um we've got some
pretty fast uh developer
processes that we use and we get by
pretty well our exposure times tend to
run about 20 to 40 seconds sort of in
that range it's even less even on the
big shots we get very bright Masters we
get real screaming bright Masters
there's a 125s I think when they're
retrofitted and reworked now they put
out about 100 or so milliwatts don't
they that's right yeah with the edelon
tuned properly we generally get 70 or 80
or even 90 when that tube is fresh
something somewhere in that range yeah
yeah they're great lasers I mean they're
you just turn them on and they go it's
just wonderful that's a lot of AG
fulfillment to have in there I bet uh
you could probably take one of those
shoots and cut it up into a four by five
inch pieces and make a fortune
these people will pay top price for that
right now I would imagine yeah not part
of my corporate charter but it's not
really what I'm interested in doing yeah
but that's true it is a lot of film and
um several artists that bought film and
had it sent here for us to keep
yeah you have a few a few lab people
that work with you or do you work pretty
much alone well I've won they're really
just two of us here that number goes up
and down a bit you know last summer I
was four um but it's been two this
winter and uh I think really that
reflects the streamlining of our
processes I used to have nine employees
um that was the max about maybe six
seven years ago and all the people that
have passed through here working here
have just done a great job in helping me
streamline all these systems so that
it could be done by one person now I
didn't let them go because of that if
you'll lay yourself off routine but they
they all really headed on to different
you know different pastures for
employment on their own pretty much
pretty much I do it but so you know the
for instance the stereogram camera that
makes masters from film footage uh it's
it's run by a small desktop computer
that's pretty automatic I
program it and it goes I know the Optics
really well I know the I know the
hardware and the Optics and I can I feel
very comfortable with that if I had to
fix it or change it modify it the
software I did not
the fellow who wrote it is still in town
and I see him a lot is your background
in Nashville physics or am I that's
correct yeah yeah I still teach
astronomy a very no math uh sort of
introductory course at the University
here University of Vermont
and we get a lot of kids that listen to
this show too because they love
Holograms especially when you get around
8th grade or so
and believe it or not a lot of them
would probably like to grow up and do
exactly what it is that you're doing
what would you have to say to them would
you advise them to look into that or
maybe not how do you feel about the the
industry itself of pornography and where
you think it's going to be maybe in
about 10 years or so do you think it's
going to be a viable industry it's going
to need
the components of it that will continue
to grow and be viable in 10 years and
probably bigger than they are now and in
particular uh those would be the attack
counterfeiting areas that I think are
still
still growing and an interferometry
measurement quality control testing with
holography is a very
variable picnic it's different ly
valuable
and there are lots and lots of spin-off
Technologies and and improvements to
those basic
their 10 or 20 years ago display
holography I would say fine art I think
the I think the applications are pretty
much Limitless I think it has a it
really can have a great future as a
medium but for commercial display which
is pretty much what we do and there's a
lot of what we do I do think the market
is dwindling I think it went frankly I'm
being very blunt here I think it went
quite a while on
a novelty appeal and it still is a very
valuable medium in its own right but it
has to be used properly to to make use
of that value and I think a lot of
commercial
Sayer designers don't don't see that
value it's our job to try to show them
and it's difficult to do that it's not
cheap I mean it's a labor-intensive
undertaking and it's not like having a
coat of chrome slide you know duped
tell us a little about your website
well
um it's uh was updated a little over a
year ago I think
my son did it actually as a computer
science student in college right now and
my instructions to him were to keep it
uh looking Snappy and
business I didn't want any kind of phony
belonging stuff but I wanted I wanted it
to look interesting and have a lot of
information on it so I think it was
exactly what I was looking for
um it said www.hola north
and there's a list of clients on there a
list of museums also collected our work
um and uh some examples of your work as
well right yeah we had a stock image
list we do about Shell stock
25 I think different images right now
and there are little black and white
pictures of of those together with
descriptions that's on that website and
considering size the price is
unbelievable well inside the Hologram we
hear it both ways yeah and some people
expect them to be 15 bucks and other
people expect them to be uh 150 000.
it's amazing there's a lot of
miscommunication or let's say
misunderstanding about holography out
there a lot of people just don't know
what it is or they think it's something
else really
um borrowed from Star Wars maybe why do
you think that is I mean
you and I admit I don't know if you
remember in New York you know one of
your shows and uh I mean we've been in
this for a long time why are we still at
the same point I mean willing then I
don't I don't see where we've moved
anywhere well in the education of the
general public yeah I think two things I
can point to uh one it is hard to
understand I think it's difficult to
really get a handle on how it works and
there are various ways to to approach
that answer or to answer that question
and all of them are kind of hard to
follow
and the other is that a lot of
misinformation is being pumped out all
the time
Hollywood I'd say in movies and TV shows
that's being put up all the time that is
called holography and it isn't it's
close
and that confuses people and I I don't
blame them I think it's very confusing
but kind of basically the the jump
that's being put up thing called
holography has a lot of advantages over
some of that stuff that's being shown in
movies and of course it also has some
disadvantages and we suffer from those
we have a show coming into a center that
I'm involved with the open day Science
and Technology Center here in the Lehigh
Valley to Lehigh University the
Discovery Center of Science and
Technology we have a traveling exhibit
from Pacific Science Center which is
coming for the summer yeah and they're
called lasers and Holograms and you have
several Holograms in there could you
tell us a little bit about what the
public can expect to see
um I'll I'll definitely remember what
they are it was a while ago that that
show was put together
um and so sometimes since we since we
gave him those Holograms but uh
as I recall there are maybe four or five
white light Transmissions
something along those lines and I think
that our T-rex skull is pretty
definitely one of those the big dinosaur
skull life size and that's that's a
great piece it's gotten a lot the manual
that was sent out for the exhibit they
have the one where uh the person this I
think it's called burst
where the person's blowing a large yes
um is the name of that piece and uh yep
it's a woman uh sort of holding a
balloon in front of her face blowing it
up and she's got her two
hand fingers are kind of spread out and
then uh into two channel hologram when
you step to the right you see the
balloon uh having disappeared and you
see her face and her hands are still
there and
be still in the motion is kind of a
blowing up this balloon but the balloon
is gone and you see both images together
they're superimposed on each other so
you see the balloon but you also see her
behind it and then the first image
disappears are they is that a pulse
hologram no uh yes it's both yeah pulse
that in Toronto with Michael souden
um research
[Music]
something like that
yeah
it's a nice piece it's a great piece I
think the other one is maybe the Space
Telescope and uh I'm just pulling this
out of memory here because I don't have
a book with me yeah you can be the album
Space Telescope yeah we have a hologram
of that and we have a hologram of the
freedom space station the U.S space
station which never got launched at
least not yet
um it does it won't look like what it
looked like back then
line and we have both of those images in
one hologram as a as a two channel
hologram that might be what they have I
think
I see
well John I want to thank you very much
for being on the show and is there
anything you want to let the listeners
know before you head out probably not
just check out our website I think
you'll find it entertaining and um you
know if you have any other uh
information you need or interest give us
a call okay and we have a link to
holographics North website right on the
whole page so you just click on that
link and off you go great that's right
John thank you very much for being a
guest on whole talk
take care